How might you use transfer learning if the data you want to work with is
如果你要处理的数据集非常庞大
very large and somewhat different than that found in the ImageNet database?
并且与 ImageNet 数据库中的图像不太相同 那么该如何使用迁移学习？
As an example, I should mention that one of Audacity's founders, Sebastian Thrun,
举个例子 优达学城创始人 Sebastian Thrun
along with a team at Stanford,
和他的斯坦福团队
recently used transfer learning to develop a CNN to diagnose skin cancer.
最近利用迁移学习开发了一个诊断皮肤癌的 CNN
The CNN classifies lesions as either benign or malignant and achieves
该 CNN 会将病灶分类为良性或恶性
performance on par with dermatologists for diagnosing some forms of skin cancer.
并且在诊断某些皮肤癌方面达到了皮肤科医生的水平
To construct his model,
他对 Inception 结构应用迁移学习
he used a transfer learning approach with the inception architecture,
并得出了皮肤癌检测模型
pre-trained on the ImageNet database.
其中 Inception 结构是在ImageNet 数据库上预训练过的模型
As a first step, he removed
首先 他删除了
the final densely connected classification layer and added a new fully-connected layer.
最后的全连接分类层并添加了新的全连接层
This is similar to the approach that I outlined before,
这和我之前介绍的方法相似
adding a new classification layer with an output size that you define.
即添加新的分类层级并且定义输出类别大小
In this case, this layer has an output value for each type of disease class.
在此例中 每种疾病类别在这一层级都有一个对应输出值
As for all the other layers in the network,
对于网络中的其他所有层级
their parameters were initialized with their pre-trained values.
使用预训练的值初始化这些参数
Then, during training, the parameters were further
在训练过程中进一步优化这些参数
optimized to fit the database of skin lesions.
以拟合皮肤病灶数据库
So, instead of using the pre-trained model as a fixed feature extractor,
Sebastian 和他的团队没有将这个预训练的模型
Sebastian and his team used it as
当做固定特征提取器
a starting point and then trained to the entire network,
而是作为起点并训练了整个网络
modifying all the weights such that they were
修改所有权重
tuned to the medical image classification task.
使它们适合处理医学图像分类任务
In this case, the model truly benefited from
在这种方式中 模型一开始能够完全受益于
the head start that it was given from pre-training on ImageNet.
在 ImageNet 上预训练的模型
This is just another kind of transfer learning.
这是另一种迁移学习
This technique is called fine tuning because it requires slightly
这种技巧称为微调
changing or tuning all the existing parameters in a pre-trained network.
因为需要稍微更改或调整预训练网络中的所有现有参数
Fine-tuning often works best if the data set you are interested in is quite large.
如果你要处理的数据集很庞大 微调通常效果最好
Transfer learning is an extremely useful technique,
迁移学习是非常有用的技巧
but you should apply it differently based on how big and how
但是你应该根据新数据集的大小
similar your data set is to the data that a pre-trained model has seen.
以及与预训练模型之间的相似程度采用不同的方式
As always, you're encouraged to experiment with different methods,
我们建议你尝试不同的方法
and you'll find more guidance on how to use
你将在下方的文本部分找到
transfer learning in a variety of scenarios in the text below.
关于如何在不同情形下使用迁移学习的更多信息